Curriculum Vitae

Betty Tsotetsi

I am detail oriented, team spirited, highly disciplined Video Wall Graphics Operator and am currently working for eNCA. Worked as an On Air Graphics operator in the same company. An in-house graphic designer and artist for a corporate branding company and an in-house graphic designer for a communications company prior to that. Among other skills, all these roles requires one to be computer literate and have in one way or the other required one to have the ability to listen attentively, pay attention to detail, multi task and also be able to work with different people and personalities. A firm believer in giving everything I do the best of me.

Experience

eNCA (2019 - Current)

Video Wall Operator

- Communicating with the team(PA, Graphics operator, Technical director, assistant production editor, server operator) to ensure that we're all working on the same piece at the same time.
- Communicating with vision control to ensure the shots can accommodate the story plasmas and vision mixer to assist when I'm still busy with shots
- Selecting images/videos for stories in the rundown and ensuring that they are suitable for and match the stories we're running
- Trouble shooting, coming up with solutions that suit whichever situation that needs attention
- Checking and playing out graphics on air
- Ensuring that graphics are working correctly
- Adjusting images and videos to match the package/story being played out

eNCA (2014 - 2019)

On Air graphics Operator

- Taking instructions from technical director and executing as required
- Working within a team to put a flawless product on air while completing individual tasks
- Trouble shooting whenever the situation requires
- Checking and playing out graphics on air
- Making sure graphics are operating correctly
- Ensuring I have correct names(correctly spelled and accompanied by correct titles) for guests

Oranges Promo (August 2011 – June 2014)

In-house graphic designer and artist

- Preparing and sending out quotes to clients
- Liaising with clients and production team to create final artworks
- Creating and ensuring that mockups are approved before final print
- Communicating with the printing team to ensure that they are aware of the set deadline
- Drawing up a schedule on what's urgent and what can be pushed back
- Following up on process with the decorators and giving feedback to customers

Zazise Communications (February 2011 - June 2011(2 Months Contract Extended))

In-house Graphic Designer

- Working with both the sales and PR teams to design promotional materials
- Putting together presentations for both the sales and PR representatives
- Creating a newspaper layout for a local(Ledig) newspaper
- Designing events promotional material from infancy to the final product for the PR side

Education

Vaal University of Technology (February 2008 - November 2010)

National diploma : Graphic Design

Thorong senior secondary school (2005) **Grade 12: (National senior certificate)**

Tools

Adobe:

- Photoshop
- Indesign
- Illustrator
- Aftereffects

Maxon:

• Cinema 4D

Viz RT:

- Multiplay
- Pilot/Director

Microsoft office:

- Powerpoint
- Word
- Outlook
- Excel

Others:

- Keynote
- VS Code

Programming:

- HTML
- Java Script
- CSS

Contact Details

Email: betty58tso@gmail.com

Mobile: 079 975 9504